Finding Aid for Department of English Language and Literature (University of Michigan) records, 1919-1994
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Topical Files
  - Departmental Files
    - English Institute, Inc., 1973-1974 (Box 6)
    - Exams (final and qualifying exams) (Box 6)
    - Faculty Files
      - Faculty promotion and salary guidelines, 1978-1979 (Box 6)
      - General Faculty Information, 1950-1977 (Box 6)
      - Gessner, Robert, 1931-1932 (Box 6)
      - Gingerrich, Solomon F., 1931-1932 (Box 6)
      - Griggs, Earl L., 1928-1931 (Box 6)
      - Jones, Howard M., 1927-1934; 2 folders (Box 6)
      - Kuyper, George A., 1920 (Box 6)
    - Faculty Meeting Minutes
      - 1967-1968 (Box 6)
      - 1972-1977 (Box 6)
    - Faculty Reviews
      - Junior Staff Reviews, 1972 (Box 9)
      - Second Term Reviews, 1975 (Box 9)
    - Freshman Composition (English 123), 1966-1973 (Box 6)
    - Freshman English Program
      - General, 1968-1975 (Box 6)
      - Statistics, 1957-1979 (Box 6)
    - Fulbright Grants, Applicant Evaluation, 1966 (Box 9)
      [SR RESTRICTED until July 1 2041 ]
    - Grade Grievance Procedures, 1974; 1981-1982 (Box 6)
    - Graduate Employee Organization
      - General, 1974-1976; 2 folders (Box 6)
      - Classroom Check, 1975 (Box 6)
      - Employee Grievances, 1974-1976; 2 folders (Box 6)
      - Fractions, undated (Box 6)
      - Irregular Arrangements Acted on, 1975 (Box 6)
      - Make-up Plans, 1975 (Box 6)
      - Responses to Form Letter, 1975 (Box 6)
      - Strike Information, 1976 (Box 6)
      - Voluntary Reportings, 1975 (Box 6)
    - Graduate Student Teaching Assistants
      - General, 1976-1983 (Box 6)
      - Manual for Introductory Composition, 1978 (Box 6)
      - Weekly Seminars, 1982-1986 (Box 6)
      - Workshops, 1980-1986; 7 folders (Box 6)
    - Grant Applications
      - 1974 (Box 6)
      - 1975 (Box 6)
      - 1978-1979 (Box 6)
      - 1980 (Box 6)
    - Great Books Program (Box 7)
    - Handbooks for Instructors, 1976-1977 (Box 7)
    - History and Constitution of Department (Box 7)
      (includes 1963, 1967, 1979, 1980 and undated)
    - Honors Program, 1971 (Box 7)
    - Inlander Literary Magazine, 1930-1931 (Box 7)
    - Interlochen, 1978 (Box 7)
    - Lectures, 1973; 1978 (Box 7)
    - Mentor Program, 1985 (Box 7)
    - MFA in creative writing program (Box 7)
    - Michigan College English Association, 1967-1971 (Box 7)
    - Michigan Council of Teachers of English, 1965 (Box 7)
    - Minority Students, 1970-1974 (Box 7)
    - Modern Languages Association, 1965-1966 (Box 7)
    - National Council of Teachers of English, 1965-1966 (Box 7)
    - National Defense Education Act Institute (NDEA), 1965-1968; 2 folders (Box 7)
    - Ogden, S., Festgabe, 1973-1974 (Box 7)
    - Organizational Charts, undated (Box 7)
    - Poetry Readings, 1968-1976 (Box 7)
    - Position Requests
      - 1968-1971 (Box 7)
      - 1973-1980, 8 folders (Box 7)
    - Program Evaluation, 1973 (Box 7)
    - Promotion Procedures and Guidelines, undated (Box 7)
    - Promotion Grievance, 1977-1978 (Box 10)
    - Promotions, 1974-1981; 4 folders (Box 10)
    - Restoration of Discipline, Memo on, 1965 (Box 7)
    - Salaries
      - General
        - 1967-1969 (Box 7)
        - 1973-1974 (Box 7)
      - Salary Comparisons, 1969-1979 (Box 7)
      - Salary Policy, 1968-1974 (Box 7)
    - Shakespeare Film Program, 1967/68 (Box 7)
    - Site Visits
      - American University, 1972 (Box 7)
      - Drake University, 1968 (Box 7)
      - Western Illinois University, 1967 (Box 7)
    - Statistics, Departmental, 1968-1974 (Box 7)
    - Study of Low Grades, 1963 (Box 10)
      [SR RESTRICTED until July 1 2038 ]
    - Summer Institute for Teachers of English, 1965-1966 (Box 7)
    - Support Staff, undated (Box 7)
    - Surveys and Questionnaires
      - Departmental Activity Survey, 1975 (Box 7)
      - Objectives of Academic Units, 1975 (Box 7)
      - Student Participation in Department Governance, 1971 (Box 7)
    - Teaching Fellows, 1966-1973 (Box 7)
    - Transfer Students, 1966 (Box 7)
    - Tuskegee Institute, 1965-1966 (Box 7)
    - United States Senators, Telegram to (re: Kent State Shootings, 1970) (Box 7)
    - Vietnam War Protest, 1969 (Box 7)
    - Writer-in-Residence Program, 1969 (Box 7)
    - Writing Laboratory and Program, 1966-1968 (Box 7)
  - University Files
    - Adult Education, Center for, 1967 (Box 8)
    - African and Afroamerican Studies, Center for, 1981 (Box 8)
    - Awards
      - Distinguished Faculty Achievement Awards, 1966-1982 (Box 8)
      - Henry Russell Award, 1966-1977 (Box 8)
      - Matthews Underclass Teaching Award, 1985 (Box 8)
    - Black Action Movement, 1970 (Box 8)
    - Clements Library, 1973; 1978 (Box 8)
    - Coalition for Use of Learning Skills, 1971-1982 (Box 8)
    - Committees
      - Academic Affairs, Advisory Committee on, 1971; 1980 (Box 8)
      - American Culture Committee, 1965 (Box 8)
      - Deanship Committee, 1967-1968 (Box 8)
      - Fundraising for the Humanities, Ad Hoc Committee on, 1975-1976 (Box 8)
      - Institutional Cooperation, Committee on, 1977-1980 (Box 8)
      - Interdepartmental Advisory Committee, 1970-1971 (Box 8)
      - LS&A Committee on the Humanities, 1966 (Box 8)
      - LS&A Curriculum Committee, 1965-1966 (Box 8)
      - LS&A Enrollment study, 1979 (Box 8)
      - Senate Advisory Committee on Undergraduate Affairs (SACUA), 1973-1979 (Box 8)
    - Comparative Literature Program, 1967-1978 (Box 8)
    - Concentration Programs, 1961-1965 (Box 8)
    - Continuing Education for Women, Center for, 1970-1973 (Box 8)
    - Coordination of Ancient and Modern Studies, Center for, 1972 (Box 8)
    - Correspondence Study Department, 1966-1970 (Box 8)
    - Education, School of, 1967-1970 (Box 8)
    - Ed. D. Program in English and Education, 1966-1981 (Box 8)
    - English Language Institute, 1964-1976 (Box 8)
    - Extension Service, University of Michigan, 1967-1975 (Box 8)
    - Flint College, 1965-1968 (Box 8)
    - Honorary Degrees, 1954-1978 (Box 8)
    - Humanities Department, College of Engineering
      - General, 1967-1975 (Box 8)
      - Review, 1970 (Box 8)
    - International Women's Year, 1975-1976 (Box 8)
    - Linguistics, Department of, 1961-1972 (Box 8)
    - LS&A Reorganization, 1965-1966 (Box 8)
    - Medieval and Renaissance Collegium, 1972-1975 (Box 8)
    - Michigan Commission on College Accreditation, 1963-1968 (Box 8)
    - Michigan Scholars in College Teaching Program, 1966-1967 (Box 8)
    - Michigan Society of Fellows, 1972-1978 (Box 8)
    - Music, School of, 1964; 1971-1972 (Box 8)
    - National Endowment for the Humanities, 1972-1974 (Box 8)
    - Phi Beta Kappa, 1967-1971 (Box 8)
    - Pilot Program, 1963; 1972 (Box 8)
    - Playwriting and Production, 1960-1969; 1972 (Box 8)
    - Rare Books and Special Collections, Department of, 1967 (Box 8)
    - Registration, 1966; 1969 (Box 8)
    - Religion, Program on Studies in, 1971-1974 (Box 8)
    - Research on Language and Language Behavior, Center for, 1965 (Box 8)
    - Research on Learning and Training, Center for, 1968; 1973-1976 (Box 8)
    - Residential College, 1964-1974 (Box 8)
    - Sesquicentennial, 1965-1966 (Box 8)
    - Speech, Communication and Theater, Department of, 1962-1975 (Box 8)
    - Teacher Certificate Program, 1963-1966 (Box 8)
    - University News Service, 1971-1972 (Box 8)
    - University Press, 1967-1975 (Box 8)
    - Walgreen Professorship, 1977; 1980 (Box 8)
    - Women's Studies, 1980-1981 (Box 8)
- Photographs
  The Photographs series consists of one undated black and white photograph of Professor Oscar J. Campbell, a member of the department from 1921 to 1936.
  - O.J. Campbell, undated; 1 photographs black and white (Box 8)